VICTOR WILLIAMS

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA

(484)-895-5489

https://www.linkedin.com/in/victorwilliams719/

victor.williams.dev@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer with strong analytical skills, proficiency in leading other engineers, and team management experience. Ability to wear many hats, such as Project Manager, Solutions Architect, Engineering Manager, or DevOps. Expertise in writing full-stack code to support multiple platforms, including Web, Android, and iOS, and a firm grasp of MERN, PERN, and MVC designs.

EDUCATION —

Temple University, Philadelphia, PA May 2019

- Bachelor of Arts:
 Computer Science and Criminal Justice
 Certificate: Computer
 Security
- Studied the subjects of Discrete Mathematics, Differential Calculus, Data Structures, Algorithms, and Operating Systems within the Computer Science Curriculum

EXPERIENCE

Feedplan

Technical Lead

- Created a marketplace platform that connects customers with discounted, prepaid meal plans from their favorite restaurants.
- Created and managed database entities and queries
- Facilitated the utilization of a Swiss army knife of point-of-sales systems
- Developed food testing platforms for the facilities of Fortune 500 companies
- **Skills:** React.js, Svelte, React, Node.js, Go, RESTfulAPI, SQL, .NETCore, MVC, C#, AWS, Azure, Java, Springboot, Python, Ionic, iOS, Android, Capacitor

Upright

Jan. 2022 - Dec. 2023

Dec. 2023 - Present

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

- Created an application for platform integration for the client side
- · Refined and improved the existing documentation within the system
- Created proof of concepts for executive research and development
- Built out features to handle banking services for users and create new fund types
- Created an automated support system to handle support items
- Created fixes for tech debt and support problems permanently solved
- **Skills:** TypeScript, React, Ruby, Python, Docker, Node.js, Azure, AWS, Go, Postgres, SQL, CI/CD Pipelines, jQuery

ACTIVITIES -

Temple University

Development Team -Eboard. Computer Science Tutor (TU), (ACM) Association for Computing Machinery, Scrum Alliance, (MLH) Major League Hacking, PennApps at UPenn, Alliance for Minority Participation in STEM. The Odyssey Online, Let's Get Ready SAT Prep Program, Owlchestra, Violinist

ORGANIZATIONS

GitHub Developer Program, Google Analytics, HackNY, TUDev, MLH Fellows, AmeriCorps, HackRU Let's Get Ready, Big Brother Big Sister, ACM, PennApps

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Analytics Academy, Twitter Flight School, Arctic Code Vault Contributor, American Red Cross Lifeguard Certificate

Racing Unleashed

Jan. 2021 – Jan. 2022

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer / Project Manager

- Designed and developed a fully integrated Coaching system with automation
- Created a 10-application ecosystem from scratch
- Reduced the number of open tickets by 87% by prioritizing all open issues
- Created an application for platform integration for the client side
- Designed and developed a fully integrated electron launcher application
- Maintained the company website in all aspects (FullStack, Cloud, CMS)
- **Skills:** TypeScript, React, Go, Electron, Node.js, Python, Craft CMS, Docker, CI/CD Pipelines, Avro Schemas, SQL, C#, Auth0, Java, SpringBoot, Kubernetes

Context Capital Partners

June 2020 - Jan. 2021

Senior Full Stack Application Engineer

- Involved in writing application-level code to interact with Web Services.
- Managed 2 outsourced tech teams from 2 countries
- Deploying and testing features to the Azure Cloud
- Developed and tested a web application with a successful production launch
- Created and maintained fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment
- **Skills:** React, Git, Go, TypeScript, Node.js, .NETCore, MVC, Python, SQL, Ajax, JSON, XML, jQuery, Azure, SCRUM, JavaScript, C#

BankMobile Nov. 2019 – June 2020

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Architecture and development of REST services powered web-based SaaS application
- Refined and improved the existing documentation within the system
- Worked in scrum process attending daily stand-up and completing tasks in sprints
- A hand in both web and mobile development
- Collaborated on a large scale with developers based around the globe
- **Skills**: .NET, Xamarin, Angular.JS, React, Python, Node.js, C#, RESTfulAPI, Azure, SCSS, SQL, jQuery, JavaScript, JSON, Visual Studio, Java, Kubernetes

CrystalFruit

Dec. 2016 – Mar. 2019

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Implemented solutions using Agile (SCRUM) methodology
- Developed Full-Stack web applications that processed, analyzed, and rendered data
- Led teams of software engineers, creating roadmap definitions, establishing engineering best practices, and mentoring other members of the team
- Maintained and updated websites upon request per client, held meetings with the team and end users to discuss product planning
- **Skills:** Azure, Vue.js, ASP.NET, React, Python, MVC, .NETCore, C#, jQuery, Git, API, SQL, Java, SpringBoot, Vue, Ruby, HTML5, CSS, Go, Node.js, JSON